Bhalaji Nagarajan

Project Engineer at Soliton Technologies

bhalaji10@gmail.com

Summary

Web based desktop applications Have been involved in developing computer software for test and measurement system for the past two years leveraging the advantages of web technologies in semiconductor industry. Have developed a simulation tool for a major semiconductor industry which has browser and desktop variants. Have been doing research on some of the latest web technologies for the usage in semiconductor industry. Specialties: Angularjs, NodeJS, HTML5 and CSS3

Experience

Project Engineer at Soliton Technologies

May 2013 - Present (2 years)

Involved in all phases of developing test and measurement software

Internship at Techieton Information Systems Private Limited

June 2012 - June 2012 (1 month)

Requirements analysis, Interface design and development for Accelerated Assessment for Rapid Response Application

Projects

Identification and Discrimination of Liver Diseases

July 2012 to May 2013

Members:Bhalaji Nagarajan, Sri Veena Nadella, madhura ranganathan

An automatic classification tool that would be able to classify ultrasound liver images based on different diseases. Mat lab was used as a development environment. A classification rate of 92% was achieved for a 10 class problem

Accelerated Assessment for Rapid Response

June 2012 to Present

Members:Bhalaji Nagarajan, vishwanath m, Sri Veena Nadella

An online examination software that was developed based on RFID based keypads. The keypads were used as an answering medium. The software had a capability of providing instant results and it had a capacity of handling 2000 people at a time

Education

Amrita School of Engineering

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Computer Science and Engineering, 2009 - 2013 Grade: 8.92/10 Activities and Societies: IEEE, ACM and CSI Chapter of Amrita. Amala Bharatam Campaign. Skills & Expertise **AngularJS** Node.js **JavaScript** C++ \mathbf{C} Java **Python** Matlab **HTML MySQL** Git **Algorithms Data Structures** Courses Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Computer **Science and Engineering** Amrita School of Engineering object oriented programming data structures algorithms operating systems database management systems cs301 **Independent Coursework**

J2SE

Certifications

Web Application Architectures

Coursera September 2014

Volunteer Experience

Cleanliness drive at Amrita Vishwa Vidyapeetham

December 2012 - Present (2 years 5 months)

Involved in a cleanliness drive in Sabarimala, Kerala which is one of the largest pilgrimage centers in South India.

Cleanliness drive at Amrita Vishwa Vidyapeetham

March 2012 - Present (3 years 2 months)

Involved in a cleanliness drive and awareness campaign in Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu

Languages

Tamil(Native or bilingual proficiency)English(Professional working proficiency)

German (Elementary proficiency)

Interests

Exploring latest technologies, Contributing to the technology, Driving social initiatives

Bhalaji Nagarajan

Project Engineer at Soliton Technologies

bhalaji10@gmail.com



Contact Bhalaji on LinkedIn